# TAYLOR FINKLEA

CLOUD SYSTEMS ENGINEERING MANAGER

## CONTACT

Kansas City, KS 66109

913-414-9496

taylor@finklea.io

https://taylor.finklea.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/taylorfinklea-8614238b/

## SKILLS

- Leadership
- Coaching and Mentorship
- All and LLMs
- Building AI Agents
- DevOps, MLOps/AlOps, CI/CD, GitOps
- Automation and Scripting
- Agile Methodology and SCRUM
- Project Management
- IT Strategy and Initiative Planning
- Cloud Cost Management
- Site Reliability
- Workload Prioritization
- Jira and Confluence
- Incident Response
- Disaster Recovery
- Business Continuity
- Technical Writing and Training
- Cloud Native Solutions
- Azure, GCP and AWS
- Automation and Scripting
- Kubernetes, Terraform and Ansible
- Systems and Network Engineering

# QUALIFICATIONS

- Management and Leadership
- 12+ years of IT Experience
- 4 years of Management Experience
- Training and Mentoring

# ATTRIBUTES

- Management and Leadership
- Dependable and Hard-Working
- Eagle Scout
- Organized
- Fast Learner

#### PROFILE

Hi there, I'm Taylor and I believe people are the most valuable asset in any organization. As the manager of Cloud Systems Engineering, I mentor and manage 14 direct reports across the Database, DevOps, and Site Reliability. I believe that collaboration and teamwork achieve incredible results compared to working in a silo. I am the leading champion and subject matter expert on implementing AI and LLMs within the organization to empower engineers. I excel at managing complex projects, cost management, MLOps/AIOps, infrastructure migration, sprint planning, coaching and mentoring, IT strategy, incident response and site reliability.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Cloud Systems Engineering Manager

TherapyNotes LLC | April 2023 - Present

- Cultivated a culture of collaboration and teamwork for over 20 direct reports across 5 teams.
- Championed adoption of AI and LLMs in the organization, including creating agents for engineering workloads.
- Managed and architected complex projects such as migrations to Terraform, GitHub Actions,
  Kubernetes.
- Partnered with other teams and departments to accomplish joint projects and initiatives.
- Maintained productivity across teams and standardized IT operations.
- Closely monitored Azure cloud costs and maintained vendor relationships.

#### DevOps and Infrastructure Manager

Lumifi Cyber Inc | Feb 2019 - April 2023

- Architected fully scalable infrastructure using Azure DevOps, Terraform, Helm, Kubernetes, Packer, Windows Virtual Desktop, Azure App Gateway, Azure WAF, Azure Firewall, Azure Virtual WAN, Azure ADDS
- Organized and completed many large-scale projects, such as a full data center migration to Azure
- Managed departments of DevOps, Infrastructure and Information Security

# Systems Administrator / Project Manager

Executech Inc. | Aug 2017 - Feb 2019

- IT consultant working for multiple government clients
- Duties include Systems Administrator, Network Administrator, Information Security, Linux Administrator
- Managing large-scale cloud, email, domain and firewall migrations

# Support Engineer

DigiCert Inc. | Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

- Assigned SSL Certificates, Client Certificates, and Code Signing
- Installed, troubleshot, and configured web servers such as IIS, Apache, and Tomcat

## IT Support Technician

Dixie State University | Nov 2014 - Aug 2015

# Remote Desktop Support Technician

ManagerPlus Solutions | Mar 2014 - Apr 2015